

502 13th Avenue E, Apt. 316, Seattle, Washington, 98102

□ (314) 954-4128 | ☑ jerry.belton@gmail.com | ♠ jcecil.io | □ jcecil | ऻ jcecil9

About Me_

Software Engineer with over 5 years of experience in the industry, primarily with Python, Java and Android looking for a role working on exciting projects and developing new skills. Excels when working with small agile teams, and proven success communicating effectively with technical and non-technical stakeholders.

Education

Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology

B.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Washington

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Terre Haute, IN

Aug. 2007 - May 2011

Seattle, WA

Aug. 2015 - PRESENT

Experience

Amazon - Device Advertising Products

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - TEST

Seattle, WA Aug. 2013 - Present

- · Increased team productivity by 15% through the creation of a unique Android application that could execute complex tasks at a push of a button, allowing internal Kindle Advertising teams to devote energy to other tasks.
- Decreased the estimated release schedule for new Over-The-Air updates for our application from 1 week down to 3 days by automating performance verification across all Kindle LCD device types, freeing up QA resources for other tasks and increasing confidence in our product.
- Developed a framework that would run automated integration tests on application builds after every new code push, allowing developers to catch bugs as soon as they are introduced, well before they ever reach customer devices.
- · Coordinated with a small team of engineers to develop an automation framework for executing test cases on various devices, from FireTV to Kindle tablets running different operating systems.
- Developed and maintained automated test suites in a continuous deployment pipeline for our backend services that create and send ads to millions of devices each day.
- · Drove several high-profile metrics processing issues to a close by constructing SQL queries to analyze production data in a unique way.

Rockwell Collins Cedar Rapids, IA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2011 - Aug. 2013

- · Coordinated with a team of engineers to implement feature requests in a C / C++ based software application; a graphics engine running on aircraft cockpit displays.
- Developed a schema verification tool in python that could automatically identify a wide variety of issues in client applications, in some cases reducing our debugging time from hours down to minutes.
- · Coordinated with teams in India and France to develop new graphical elements in our engine and debug issues in their development environments.

Projects.

#Beer_Tapp http://107w.io/

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2016 - PRESENT

· Worked with a group of talented engineers to develop 107w.io; a website designed to help users choose a beer from the tap list at a bar, given a list of beers that the user previously enjoyed.

Jcecil I/O jcecil.io

WEB DEVELOPER Oct. 2014 - PRESENT

• Developed a personal website to post progress updates on projects, and acts as a server for chromecast and other test applications.

Skills

Programming Java, Python, C/C++, GoLang, Julia, OpenGL, Vulkan

> Web HTML, Javascript, Django with Python

Appium (automation framework), Android, Chromecast, Linux (bash, vim, grep) Applications